webhostingrating.com 2015-06-09

# Privacy Policy | WebHostingRating.net

## PRIVACY POLICY

WebhostingRating GmbH (hereinafter, referred to as “Company” or “We” or “Us” or “Our”) owns, manages, and operates WebhostingRating.net (hereinafter, referred to as “Website”) The Company respects the online privacy of the users of this Website (hereinafter, referred to as “You” or “Your’). This Privacy Policy (hereinafter, referred to as “Policy”) outlines Our practices on how We collect, retain, use, disclose and protect Your personal and non-personal information while You browse through this Website.

### Personal Information - Collection, Retention, and Usage

While submitting Your company for reviewing purposes on this Website, We collect certain personal information including, but not limited to, Your name, email address, company name, URL, physical address of Your company including continent, Your preferred username and password. This information is used to deliver efficient services to the users of this Website. We also use this information to inform You about the latest news, announcements, website updates, special offers, and events that You might be interested in. However, You can contact us if You don’t wish to receive any communication from Us. Upon receipt of such request, We shall delete Your email address from Our mailing list within a reasonable period of time.

While rating a host company, We collect certain personal information including, but not limited to, Your name and URL of Your website. We use this information for verification purposes in order to prevent the abuse of rating system offered on this Website. This information is not used for any unsolicited communications or promotional messages.

All the personal information so collected shall be retained for as long as it is needed by Us for administrative purposes and legal purposes.

Your personal information shall be kept private and confidential. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise commercially exploit Your personal information so collected.

### Non-Personal Information - Collection, Retention, and Usage

When You visit this Website, certain non-personal information is automatically collected by the inbuilt coding that is part of the Website backend. Such information includes, but not limited to, the Internet Protocol (IP) Address of Your computer, the browser You used to access this Website, operating system installed on Your computer, Your Internet Service Provider’s (ISP’s) IP Address, etc. This information is used to enhance Your browsing experience of this Website. This information is also used for troubleshooting purposes. In addition, We also collect such non-personal information for internal research purposes on Our user’s demographics, interests and behavior; and to improve Our overall business practices.

All the non-personal information so collected shall be retained for as long as it is needed by Us for administrative and legal purposes.

We may share Your non-personal information with Our affiliates, advertisers, agents, and/or partners for administrative and advertisement purposes.

### Cookies

For the collection of non-personal information, this Website employs cookies, which are small text files placed on the hard drive of Your computer system. These cookies do not collect any personal information You provide, but they may be linked to such personally identifiable information. For instance, cookies may be used to store username and password when You log-in in order to prevent You from entering username and password every time You access different pages of this Website, while the session is still on. However, You can still disable the cookies by managing Your browser’s preferences.

We also use cookies to detect manipulation of webhost ratings and multiple reviews submissions.

In addition, advertisers, affiliates, and/ or partners that place their advertisements on this Website may also use their own cookies. We shall not be liable for any information collected by them from the users of this Website by using their own cookies. **  
**

### Third-Party Links

This Website may contain links to other websites of promoters, advertisers, affiliates, partners, agents, etc. We do not review, control, monitor, or endorse the privacy practices of such linked third-party websites. Your use of such linked websites shall be subject to the legal policies of these websites.

### Security and Protection

We employ latest industry-standard technological safeguards to secure the transmission of all kinds of information through this Website. We also take other reasonable steps to prevent loss, misuse, and alteration of information so collected. No unauthorized personnel are allowed to access any personal information.

However, in the wake of sophistication of technology, We cannot guarantee foolproof security in the event of an unauthorized breach of security measures.

### Disclosure of Information

We shall not disclose or share Your information so collected in any manner that is not in pursuance of this Policy, except under the following circumstances:

  1. Disclosure to government agencies in response to legal processes, like subpoena; or
  2. Any unlawful or unauthorized access to, and transmissions of, personal information from this Website; or
  3. Disclosure of personal information by the user himself or herself, on online Message Boards, Public Forums, blogs, social networking sites, or any other online or offline media; or
  4. Disclosure in order to protect Our interests and enforce Our Terms of Use Agreement; or
  5. Disclosure to trusted third parties who may be appointed to assist Us in case of investigating any illegal activity on this Website; or
  6. Disclosure as an asset in conjunction with the sale, or part sale, of this Website to a third party.

### Changes & Updates in Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change and update any portion of this Privacy Policy, in whole or in part, at any time for any reason and without any notice to anyone. All such changes shall be effective from the time they are posted on this page.

### Last Updated on: January 31, 2011.

### Contact

Please free to contact us in case of doubts on this Privacy Policy by email (mailbox@WebhostingRating.net).
